Ollie Wright Game Designer/Programmer

Wallingford, Oxfordshire

Portfolio: ollieportfolio.com

PROFILE

As a game developer with 6 years of experience with game creation, I have strong foundations in a number of design disciplines, programming (specialising in AI and systems development), and an understanding of the QA process. I graduated with a First Class degree in computer games technology, creating a number of the highest graded games in my class, including a showcase of a group project at the Barclays Game Frenzy 2024, and a solo project at my university's Graduate Showcase the year prior, where it received acclaim from developers at Larian Studios. My commitment to learning is demonstrated by my most recent project of building a portfolio in order to teach myself HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

EXPERIENCE

Curation, University Project — Design and Al Programming September 2023 - May 2024

Curation is a museum management simulation game created alongside Frontier Developments. I focused on creating NPCs that displayed personality and encouraging emergent gameplay through their behaviour, and the underlying system/tech design. This project was showcased at the Barclays Game Frenzy 2024 event in Canary Wharf. Skills: Unity, C#, Modular AI behaviour, Technical Design, System Design, QA

Press Space, University Project — Solo (design, code, art) February 2023 - May 2023

Press Space is a satirical branching narrative game, featuring nine different endings. The game was designed to critique the relationship between players and developer, as well as the concept of free will within games, and I handled all aspects of development. Skills: Design for game feel, C#, Narrative design, Full stack development

Cedrik's Crown, University Project — Lead Designer & QA October 2022 - January 2023

Cedrik's Crown is a 2-4 player dungeon crawler RPG board game. The enemy encounters were balanced by a program written by myself in C++. I focused mostly on the core gameplay loop and the player experience, in addition to playtesting and iterating extensively in order to ensure balance and consistent player engagement. Skills: Design principles and balancing, team leadership, C++, QA

EDUCATION

University of Portsmouth, Portsmouth — First Class degree in Computer Games Technology (BSc) – September 2021 - July 2024

Graduated with a 4.16 GPA, with each year module mark average being First Class

The Henley College, Henley — A-Levels – May 2021

Maths (A) Economics (A) Computer Science (A)



ollieswright02@gmail.com



+44 7415 346 751



in <u>linkedin.com/in/ollieswright</u>



github.com/OllieGuy

PROFICIENCIES

Visual Studio 2022/VSCode Unity & PlasticSCM Git/GitHub

C#

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Confluence Microsoft Office suite Adobe Photoshop Adobe Premiere Pro

SOFT SKILLS

Working with small and medium sized teams to strict

Meeting and engaging with new people at conferences and

Very strong work ethic and willingness to learn

Positive attitude/outlook and

INTERESTS

Full stack Game Development

Design iteration and

Media Theory and films

Video and board gaming